Finding Aid for the Getty Research Institute Scholars Program Images and Recordings, 1985-2013 IA20026
Institutional Records and Archives
- Audio recordings, 1987-2001; Series I.; 21.7 Linear Feet (27 boxes); 1741.37 GB (944 files)
  - Scholar Year 1988-1989, Series I.C.; 66.09 GB (29 files)
    Materials comprise recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1988/1989. During this time Getty Scholars focused on the distinctive qualities of cultural products selected for historical analysis or the ways in which scholarly interpretations are linked to particular methodological and theoretical assumptions. Many stressed close observation of cultural customs, traditions, and patterns of production. Others examined disciplinary practices and their interpretive strategies. Vital contributions were made toward fashioning interdisciplinary approaches for analyzing cultural continuities and changes. This group of scholars was drawn from the fields of anthropology, ethnography, the history of art, social history, and sociology. While many of the lectures given during this academic year were inspired by the scholar theme "The Production of Artifacts and the Formation of Disciplines," some of the lectures are not thematically related.
    - Otto Wagner Symposium, November 3-5, 1988; Series I.C.1.; (12 audiocassettes)
      - Session 1:, November 3, 1988
        - Forster, Kurt. Opening remarks (introduced by Herb Hymans), 0047b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Geraniotis, Roula. [Ricker's translation of Wagner's Moderne Architektur and its impact on American architecture], 0047b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Moravanszky, Akos. "The Aesthetics of the Mask: Otto Wagner and Architectural Theory in Central Europe", 0048a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Discussion of the Geraniotis and Moravanszky lectures, 0048b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
          Recording begins mid-sentence. Audio quality is poor. Voices are faint and there is a buzzing sound in the foreground through much of the recording.
        - Kassal-Mikula, Renata. [Otto Wagner's Parallel Aktion], 0049a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Whyte, Iain Boyd. [Outstanding students of the Wagnerschule: Emil Hoppe, Marcel Kammerer, and Otto Schönthal], 0049a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Sekler, Eduard F. "Criticism and Commenmoration of Otto Wagner by His Students...", 0050b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Discussion of Whyte and Sekler lectures on the Wagnerschule, 0050a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
      - Session 2:, November 4, 1988
        - Neumeyer, Fritz. "Grobstadt Architektur: Architectural Practice in the Great City" lecture and discussion, 0051a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
          Recording includes brief welcome by Herb Hymans and introduction by session mediator, Werner Oechslin.
        - Buddensieg, Tilmann. [Wagner and Messel...Vienna and Berlin] lecture and discussion, 0051b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Sarnitz, August. [Realism versus, Verniedlichung: The Design of the Great City], 0053b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Mallgrave, Harry F. "The Polemics of Architectural Realism in Germany and Austria", 0053a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Discussion, 0054b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Oechslin, Werner. "The Evolutionary Way Toward Modern Architecture: Otto Wagner's Architecture and the Paradigm of Stilhülse und Kern", 0054a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
      - Session 3:, November 5, 1988
        - Anderson, Stanford. "Sachlichkeit and Modernity: Life Without Magnificence", 0055 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Discussion, 0056b (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Unidentified speaker. "Ruminations on Modern Architecture and Impressionism", 0056a (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        - Final discussion and closing remarks, 0057 (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
    - Lectures and presentations, Series I.C.2.; (12 audiocassettes)
      - AIDS discussion, 1988; 0059; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
        Lecture begins mid-sentence without the benefit of an introduction.
      - Goody, Sir John (Jack) Rankine. "Paradise, Garlands, and Sacrifice,", January 9, 1989; 0061; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-2)
      - Sanday, John. "Architectural Conservation in Nepal: The Rebirth of Traditional Crafts,", January 18, 1989; 0062; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
        Recording ends mid-sentence.
      - Settis, Salvatore. "Deceptive Walls: Imagery and Space in Roman Garden Painting,", February 13, 1989; 0063; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - García Rodero, Cristina. "Photographing Spanish Fiestas,", February 27, 1989; 0064; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Janda, Annegret. "The Modern Art Collection of the Kronprizen Palais in Berlin from 1918 Until its Confiscation as Degenerate Art in 1937,", April 3, 1989; 0065; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Buddensieg, Tilman. "Montfaucon L'Antiquité Expliqué: The End of a Continuous Antiquity,", May 1, 1989; 0068; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Bohrer, Frederick. "The Reception of Assyria: Archaeology and Orientalism,", May 10, 1989; 0069a; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Bohrer Discussion, 0069b; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Heinz, Thomas. "L.A. Architecture" tour lecture, May 12, 1989; 0070; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Gurevich, Aron. "Angry Saints and Good Demons in the 13th Century Exempla,", May 22, 1989; 0071; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
        Audio quality is inconsistent once the question and answer session begins.
  - Scholar Year 1989-1990, Series I.D.; 52.04 GB (18 files)
    Materials comprise recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1989/1990. During this year the Getty Scholars played an important role in the development of a more comprehensive and interdisciplinary approach to the arts of the early twentieth century, especially those called avant-garde, by increasing our understanding of the cultures in which they flourished. The fields of interest represented included comparative literature, the history of art and architecture, musicology, psychology, and film history. While most of the lectures given during this academic year were inspired by the scholar theme "The Avant-Garde," some of the lectures are not thematically related.
    - Silver, Kenneth. "Andy Warhol Soup to Nuts,", November 20, 1989; 0080; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Spielmann, Yvonne. "Rumours on the Demise of the Avant-Garde,", December 4, 1989; 0081; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Bucher, François, 1989 (?); 0094; (1 audiocassette)
      Recording device frequently fades in and out from the audible to the silent. Engineer attempted to increase volume as much as possible. But white background noise persists throughout.
      - "Le Point de Leur Mestier: The 'Secret' Methods of Gothic Architecture," Part 1, 0094a (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - "Le Point de Leur Mestier: The 'Secret' Methods of Gothic Architecture," Part 2, 0094b (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Mainardi, Patricia. "The Academic Reaction in the Third Republic,", January 29, 1990; 0097; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Brown, Andreas. "Vintage Photographic Postcards as a Significant Source of Early 20th Century American Imagery,", February 5, 1990; 0098; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      Many pauses evident in audio due to the slideshow shown by speaker in lecture (in which he would allow the audience to view slides for long stretches of time). Longest silences were edited down to a few seconds to make listening experience more efficient.
    - Letheic, Michel. "The Clarinet Around the World,", February 22, 1990; 0099; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      Inaudible/Silent Portion Deleted
      After the first applause after the performance, a few minutes is cut out because there is no discernible audio in that portion. At 36 minutes and 12 seconds, one question was recorded and then the presentation concludes with closing applause.
    - Girth, Peter. "Musical Avant-Garde and Politics,", February 26, 1990; 100; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Phillips, Christopher. "Cultural Modernity and the Illustrated Press Between the Wars,", March 12, 1990; 104; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Herbert, James. "Matisse and Derain in the South of France: Tourism and the Picturesque,", April 9, 1990; 105; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Wyss, Beat. "Ragnorök of Illusion: Wagner's Mystical Abyss at Bayreuth,", April 19, 1990; 106; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Mutlow, John. "Architecture Tour Lecture,", April 20, 1990; 107 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      No digital file found for this lecture.
    - Murray, Irena. "Under the Banner of the Book: The Work of Karel Teige,", April 23, 1990; 0108; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Reese, Tom, Herb Hymans, Dan Haulica, Danie-Constantin Barbu, Theodor Enescu, Zoe Petre, Geo Sherban-Constantin, April 26, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
      - "The Current Situation of Rumania's Cultural Patrimony," Part 1, 0109 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - "The Current Situation of Rumania's Cultural Patrimony," Part 2, 0110 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Gottlieb, Robert and April Smith. "Earth Day 1990 and Environmental Responsibility at the Institutional Level,", April 27, 1990; 0111; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Ballerini, Luigi. "Neither Rhyme nor Reason: A Case of Punctuation,", April 30, 1990; 0112; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
    - Jelavich, Peter, May 21, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
      - "Girls and Crisis," Part 1, 0113 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - "Girls and Crisis," Part 2, 0114 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
  - Scholar Year 1990-1991, Series I.E.; 187.17 GB (82 files)
    Materials comprise recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1990/1991. This scholar year was originally centered around classical antiquity. A broad spectrum of scholars working in that field were invited, together with a smaller satellite group working on the Ancient Near East, Africa, Pre-Columbian America, and Asia. The group of scholars who accepted the invitation engaged in a rich comparativist interplay related to their studies in Pre-Columbian and colonial Peru, Africa, the Ancient Near East, Etruscan Italy, and the Hellenistic world. In the end, only Asia was unrepresented. While most of the lectures given during this academic year were inspired by the scholar theme "Time and Ritual in Antiquity," some of the lectures are not thematically related.
    - Architectural Adumbrations Series: The Architect's Sketchbook and Contemporary Practice, November-December 1990; Series I.E.1.; (9 audiocassettes and 1 copy)
      Materials comprise recordings of lectures presented in conjunction with the exhibition, "Architectural Adumbrations: The Architect's Sketchbook and Contemporary Practice," which was held at the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities in Santa Monica, California from September 1990 to February 1991.
      - Norten, Enrique. [Personal architectural style], November 19, 1990; 0133 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        Incomplete recording. Lecture seems to end abruptly.
      - Mack, Mark. [Personal history of drawings and sketches], November 27, 1990; 0136 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Jiménez, Carlos. [Ruminations on the notion of drawing], November 27, 1990; 0137 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Wolf, Harry. [Prelude to a conversation: A discussion on three buildings and their drawings], December 4, 1990; 0138 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Israel, Franklin. [The Sketch As An Idea Development and the Constructed Drawing: A lecture on presented exhibition pieces and other personal works], December 4, 1990; 0139 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Predock, Antoine. [Innocent lines and architecture as landscape and drag], December 11, 1990; 0144 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Coenen, Jo. [The repairing of places: a new identity and characteristic on a modern basis], December 11, 1990; 0145 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Gehry, Frank O. [The private side of architectural design], December 18, 1990; 0148 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Holl, Stephen. [Phemonology and crudeness in architecture], December 18, 1990; 0149 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
    - Anyone Conference, May 1991; Series I.E.2.; (23 audiocassettes)
      The Anyone Conference was held at the University of California, Los Angeles. This conference was the first in a series of Any conferences, which took place in the decade leading up to the year 2000. Multidisciplinary and cross-cultural in nature, the "Any" conferences focused on the condition of architecture at the end of the millennium. Participants in the 1991 conference included Akira Asada, Francesco Dal Co, Jacques Derrida, Peter Eisenman, William Gibson, Arata Isozaki, Fredric Jameson, Kojin Karatani, Jeffrey Kipnis, Rem Koolhaas, Rosalind Krauss, Rafael Moneo, John Rajchman, Ignasi de Solà-Morales Rubió, David Salle, R.E. Somol, Mark C. Taylor, Roberto Mangabeira Unger, and Anthony Vidler. Materials comprise master audiocassettes, as well as copies.
      Lectures that were conducted at the conference, but of which audio files were not found, include: Ignasi de Solà-Morales Rubió: "From Autonomy to Untimeliness"; Frank Gehry: "Hook, Line, and Signature"; Maria Nordman: "Infinite Openness"; and Daniel Libeskind: "ANYONE? A Text for a Ventriloquist."
      Additional information can be found at http://www.anycorp.com/any_conferences.php
      Several lectures are incomplete due to missing cassette recordings or inadvertent loss during the transfer process from cassette tapes to computer audio files.
      - Forster, Kurt. [Opening remarks and introduction for Peter Eisenman], 0189a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Eisenman, Peter. [Origin and mission statement of Anyone Conference], 0189a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Davidson, Cynthia. "In Any Event," [introduction of lecturers and the Any journal], 0189a3 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Kipnis, Jeff. "Three Questions of Anyone", 0189a4 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Karatani, Kojin. "The Status of an Individual", 0189a5 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Unger, Roberto Mangabeira. "The Better Futures of Architecture", 0189b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Karatani, Kojin and Roberto Unger. "Impromptu remarks," [moderated by Jeff Kipnis], 0189b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Derrida, Jacques. "Summary of Impromptu Remarks," [moderated by Jeff Kipnis], 0190a (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Karatani, Kojin and Robert Unger. "Closing remarks," [moderated by Jeff Kipnis], 0190b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Jameson, Fredric. "Demographies of the Anonymous", 0190b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Asada, Akira and Arata Isozaki. "A Fragmentary Portrait of Anyone as Demiourgos", 0195 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Asada, Akira and Arata Isozaki. "Discussion A-1," [moderated by Jeff Kipnis], 0196a (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Koolhaas, Rem. "Precarious Entity", 0196b (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Taylor, Mark C. "The Subject of Architecture", 0197 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Gibson, William. "Text[v]oid", 0198a1 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Koolhaus, Rem, William Gibson, and Mark C. Taylor. "Discussion A-2," [moderated by Anthony Vidler], 198a2 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Krauss, Rosalind. "Six Notes on the Subject of the Grid," [Read by Sylvia Lavin], 0199 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Eisenman, Peter. "The Author's Affect: Passion and the Moment of Architecture", 0206 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Vidler, Anthony. "Transparency", 0207 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Eisenman, Peter, Sylvia Lavin and Anthony Vidler. "Discussion A-3", 0208 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Somol, R.E. "RE: The Subject of Disappearance", 0214b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Salle, David. "The Style, the Image, and the Arbitrary", 0214b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Rajchman, John. "On Not Being Any One", 0214b3 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Moneo, Rafael. "Cualquiera", 0215b1 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Dal Co, Francesco, Daniel Libeskind, Rafael Moneo, John Rajchman, and R.E. Somol. "Discussion B-1", 0215b2 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
        Missing Segment
        Conclusion to lecturers' discussion missing.
      - Forster, Kurt. [Closing Remarks to Anyone Conference, introduced by Kurt Forster], 0219 (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
    - Lectures and presentations, Series I.E.3.; (51 audiocassettes and 1 copy)
      - Vikan, Gary, October 9, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "The Empowered Object: Idols and Icons in Late Antiquity," Part 1 Lecture, 0119 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
        - "The Empowered Object: Idols and Icons in Late Antiquity," Part 2 Discussion, 0120 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - McClellan, Andrew, November 7, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "Display Strategies at the Dawn of the Museum Age: From the Bourbons to Bonaparte," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0129 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
        - "Display Strategies at the Dawn of the Museum Age: From the Bourbons to Bonaparte," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0130 (Box 1996.IA.02-3)
      - Stafford, Barbara M., November 13, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "Voyeur or Observer? Enlightenment Thoughts on the Dilemmas of Display," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0131 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Voyeur or Observer? Enlightenment Thoughts on the Dilemmas of Display," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0132 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Wyss, Beat, November 20, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "Progress or Eternal Return: Two Museological Tendencies in German Idealism," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0134 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Progress or Eternal Return: Two Museological Tendencies in German Idealism," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0135 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
          General Note
          Most questions are missing in question and answer session. Answers are discernable though.
      - Nono, Luigi. "Sofferte onde Serene (1976)" with Gloria Cheng on piano, December 7, 1990; 0141; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - White, Hayden, December 10, 1990; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "Tropology," Part 1, 0142 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Tropology," Part 2, 0143 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Settis, Salvatore. "From Ruins to Museums: The Fortunes of Classical Sculpture," Lecture and Discussion, January 15, 1991; 0152-0153
        - Original recordings, (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - Use copies, (3 CDs) (Enclosure 1996.IA.02-36)
      - Sheehan, James J., January 29, 1991; (3 audiocassettes)
        - "Aesthetic Theory and Architectural Practice: Schinkel's Museum in Berlin," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0156 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Aesthetic Theory and Architectural Practice: Schinkel's Museum in Berlin," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0158 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Karp, Ivan, February 5, 1991; (3 audiocassettes)
        - "Exhibiting Cultures: Towards a Critical Examination of Ethnographic Display," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0160 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Exhibiting Cultures: Towards a Critical Examination of Ethnographic Display," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0161 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Exhibiting Cultures: Towards a Critical Examination of Ethnographic Display," Lecture and Discussion, Part 3, 0165 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Larsen, Mogens, February 11, 1991; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "The Death of Mesopotamian Civilization," Part 1, 0162 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "The Death of Mesopotamian Civilization," Part 2, 0163 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Zuidema, Tom. "Spanish Myth and Andean Reality: How the Feast of Corpus Christi Shaped Our View of Inca Royalty,", March 4, 1991; 0168; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
      - Lowry, Glenn, March 5, 1991; (5 audiocassettes)
        - "Islamic Art and the Politics of Perception: Display and Interpretation," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0171 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
        - "Islamic Art and the Politics of Perception: Display and Interpretation," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0172 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
        - "Islamic Art and the Politics of Perception: Display and Interpretation," Lecture and Discussion, Part 3, 0169 (Box 1996.IA.02-4)
        - "Islamic Art and the Politics of Perception: Display and Interpretation," Lecture and Discussion, Part 4, 0173 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Archer, John. "Black and White Space: The Spatial Formation of Calcutta, 1690-1850,", March 11, 1991; 0174; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Marinetti, Luce. "Poetry and Futurism,", March 19, 1991; 0175; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Rossi, Aldo. "At the Getty Center,", March 19, 1991; 0176; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Krenek, Ernst. "Sonata for solo violin, op. 33,", March 22, 1991; 0177; (1 audiocassette and 1 copy) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Behn, Robin."Poetry Reading,", March 25, 1991; 0179; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Conforti, Michael. "The Applied Arts Enter the Museum: European Origins--American Extensions,", March 26, 1991; 0181; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
        Audio recording of lecture is incomplete and question and answer session was not recorded.
      - Moravánszky, Akos. "Embroidered Stones,", April 1, 1991; 0182; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Bonta, Dr. Juan Pablo. "A Software and Database Project: 'American Architects and Texts: A Study of Critical Fortune in Architectural Literature,'", April 4, 1991; 0183; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Stewart, Andrew. "Inter Tabula Nullis Postferenda: Heroism, Frustration, Tragedy, and Chance in the Alexander Mosaic,", April 17, 1991; 0184; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
      - Von Huene, Stephan. "Introduces the Artwork of Stephan Von Huene,", April 22, 1991; 0185
        - Original recording, (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
        - Use copy, (1 CD) (Enclosure 1996.IA.02-36)
      - Kaufman, Edward, April 23, 1991; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "Museums of Architecture: Preservation, Display, and the Value of Heritage," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0186 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
          Audio recording from first portion of lecture was indiscernible; audio recording is therefore incomplete.
        - "Museums of Architecture: Preservation, Display, and the Value of Heritage," Lecture and Discussion, Part 2, 0187 (Box 1996.IA.02-5)
          Audio recording of discussion ends abruptly and is likely incomplete.
      - MacCormack, Sabine. "Limits of Understanding: Perceptions of Greco-Roman and Amerindian Paganism in Early Modern Europe,", May 13, 1991; 0220; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Hofmann, Werner. "The Promising Shrine: Image-Magic and the Museum," Lecture and Discussion, May 14, 1991; 0221; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Gisbert, Teresa. "Indigenous Aspects of Andean Baroque,", May 16, 1991; 0223; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Blier, Suzanne Preston. "Paradoxes in African Art: On the Meeting of Incongruity, Antipathy, and Enigma,", May 20, 1991; 0224; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
        Recording of lecture ends mid-sentence (incomplete).
      - Fabian, Johannes. "Curios and Curiosity: About Objects and Ethnography,", May 28, 1991; 0225; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
      - Severin, Ingrid. "Wilhelm von Bode and the Origin of the Asiatic Museums in Berlin,", June 3, 1991; 0227; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
        Question and answer session ends abruptly.
      - Samonà, Alberto. "A New Approach to the Preservation of the Past in Italy: The Archaeological Park of Orvieto,", June 4, 1991; 0228; (1 audiocassette)
        Lecture incomplete. Only beginning portion of presentation available.
        - Original recording, (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-6)
        - Use copy (Enclosure 1996.IA.02-36)
      - Talvacchia, Bette, June 5, 1991; (2 audiocassettes)
        - "An Evening with Giulio Romano," Lecture and Discussion, Part 1, 0229a (Box 1996.IA.02-6)